<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog of Dale Knauss</title>
    <description>code, people, and strange things that go bump in the night.
</description>
    <link>daleknauss.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="daleknauss.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 12:40:54 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 12:40:54 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Posts and Talks on Virtual and Augmented Reality</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After having spent loads of time working with the HTC Vive, Oculus Rift, Hololens, and other VR and AR headsets, I’m a raving convert to the idea that Virtual and Augmented Reality will collectively be the next major medium embraced by entertainment and gaming companies, but also by businesses seeking to build serious applications that solve real user needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, I’ve written a few articles exploring some important parts of building VR applications. I’m also scheduled to do a few presentations this year where I’ll be helping web developers make the transition into building experiences for Virtual Reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;talks&quot;&gt;Talks:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developerweek2017.sched.com/event/921X&quot;&gt;The Web Developer’s Guide to Virtual Reality&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://developerweek.com/&quot;&gt;Developer Week 2017&lt;/a&gt; - San Francisco, USA - February 15th&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2017.mceconf.com/speakers.html&quot;&gt;Introduction To Virtual Reality Development With Unity&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://2017.mceconf.com/&quot;&gt;MCE 2017&lt;/a&gt; - Warsaw, Poland - May 9th&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;posts&quot;&gt;Posts:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mindtheproduct.com/2016/11/virtual-reality-and-your-product-development-process/&quot;&gt;Virtual Reality and Your Product Development Process&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://presencepress.presencepg.com/&quot;&gt;Presence Press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://presencepress.presencepg.com/why-unity-will-power-the-future-of-virtual-and-augmented-reality-6e79960fbce4#.ha5m3v6zt&quot;&gt;Why Unity Will Power the Future of Virtual and Augmented Reality&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mindtheproduct.com/&quot;&gt;Mind The Product&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 04:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>daleknauss.com/virtual-augment-reality</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">daleknauss.com/virtual-augment-reality</guid>
        
        
        <category>virtual-reality</category>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Javascript and Node.js - The World Domination Tour</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Awhile back I wrote a piece on Javascript’s ever growing attempts at world domination. It’s my most popular article ever with almost 30,000 views on Medium! If you’re interested in the future of Javascript and Node, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://presencepress.presencepg.com/javascript-and-node-js-continue-to-eat-the-world-d41918a0615b&quot;&gt;Javascript (and Node.js) Continues To Eat The World&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 04:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>daleknauss.com/recent-writing</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">daleknauss.com/recent-writing</guid>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Guide For Junior Developers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote a post on Medium: &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/presence-product-group/the-seven-habits-of-a-highly-effective-junior-developer-ac4d0f72c24e#.7wjnh246e&quot;&gt;The Seven Habits of a Highly Effective Junior Developer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the bullet points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn Voraciously&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ask Great Questions&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Clean Code Matters&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fail Often — Fail Well&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tackle Bite-size Problems&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Build Things&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Soft Skills Matter&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/presence-product-group/the-seven-habits-of-a-highly-effective-junior-developer-ac4d0f72c24e#.7wjnh246e&quot;&gt;the whole thing&lt;/a&gt; a read if you’re into that sort of thing!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>daleknauss.com/guide-for-junior-developers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">daleknauss.com/guide-for-junior-developers</guid>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why you shouldn't learn to code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a common suggestion: “everyone should learn to code” or at least “if you’re trying to start a new online business, you should build your own MVP.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people go so far as to say that the ability to code is the new literacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who learned to code after college and one failed business, and currently does it professionally, I call bullshit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;coding-is-ing-hard&quot;&gt;1. Coding is $^#@ing hard!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, if you’ve never done anything intensely technical before, this is going to be one hell of a wild ride. Your brain will be stretched in a million ways. You’ve never thought about the world like this. There are a million things to learn, and once you’ve learned them, half of them are no longer the right way to do things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-takes-way-longer-to-master-than-you-expect&quot;&gt;2. It takes way longer to master than you expect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m three years into my career as a professional programmer now. I still feel like the mysteries of developing high-quality, scalable products are an enigma wrapped in a riddle wrapped in bacon. Sure, I can build most anything I put my mind to now, and I’m pretty proud of how far I’ve come. Unfortunately, there are so many aspects to building high-quality software that I feel like I could learn for the rest of my life and still not be where I want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;youre-not-going-to-love-it-unless-you-do&quot;&gt;3. You’re not going to love it (unless you do)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding is the type of thing you have to love. It’s a lot of long hours in front of a screen. It’s a never ending sequence of bugs, merge conflicts, regressions, and other nasty sounding time sucks. Unless you love the art of coding, savor the ability to bring something from your mind into reality, and crave the sweet release of finely crafted code running smoothly on computers all around the world, it’s not for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-not-the-only-skill&quot;&gt;4. It’s not the only skill&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because coding is essential to building many types of startups doesn’t mean it’s the only important skill. A good developer often flails around hopelessly when it comes to design, sales, marketing, operations, or a number of other essential skills. If those areas are more appealing to you, embrace them. Get really good at them and you’ll be every bit as valuable as a good developer. Don’t buy the myth that code is everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technical-literacy-is-not-as-important-as-literacy&quot;&gt;5. Technical literacy is NOT as important as literacy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to use and understand existing software is pretty essential. Being able to write code is an entirely different matter. The ability to write loops and conditional statements is great and all but it’s not like being able to read. If your area of expertise isn’t coding, you’re better off mastering the software of your trade (no loops required) then knowing the internals of javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-might-like-it-too-much&quot;&gt;6. You might like it too much&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one I didn’t expect. When I started learning, I gave myself two years and then I would start another business. It never occurred to me that I would love it. It has been four years now and I love writing code. I have an amazing team, I’m constantly challenged and growing, and I’m excited for the future. In other words: “It’s a trap!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;before-you-throw-in-the-towel&quot;&gt;Before you throw in the towel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said all that, I have zero regrets about becoming a software developer. It has enriched my life in so many amazing ways and opened countless opportunities for me. What’s more it has allowed me to build whatever I can dream up without relying on anyone else. Never again do I have to convince someone else to build an idea for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I suggest is that before you jump head first into learning to code, make sure you understand what you’re getting in to and make absolutely sure that you LOVE it. If you don’t, there are easier ways to get where you’re going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>daleknauss.com/why-you-shouldnt-learn-to-code</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">daleknauss.com/why-you-shouldnt-learn-to-code</guid>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In Defense of Ideas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a score to settle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may call me a ne’er-do-well, a rabble rouser, or a malcontent. But for too long justice has been subverted and the bourgeoisie has stood in the way of something beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I speak of course of the poor, misunderstood, and often maligned &lt;strong&gt;idea&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Ideas are worthless, execution is everything.” — Every Author/Blogger&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argument against ideas is varied and I won’t attempt to recreate it perfectly here. The gist of it is that a great founding team coupled with flawless execution, perfect timing, and a whole lot of luck is what it takes to succeed with a startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas, the theory goes, aren’t worth a dime. Everyone has them and they won’t get you anywhere on their own. What’s more, most ideas are flat out wrong and will require serious iterations if not total reversals in an attempt to find a business that works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compounding the problem, you have self-professed “idea people” who bring little to the table beyond their “world-changing” idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-case-for-ideas&quot;&gt;The case for ideas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, execution is vital and close to my heart. However, ideas, good and otherwise, are the lifeblood that keeps our wonderful world pulsing with energy and soaring torwards greater heights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, the founding team is critical and many investors will look past terrible ideas if the team is right. But without faith that a team will eventually produce a great idea, no money would ever change hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolutely, if you don’t have great timing and a whole lot of luck, you’re dead in the water. Though, that’s the case with or without a great idea so that’s a wash (pun intended).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you’ll get no argument from me that “idea people” aren’t worth a whole lot once you get going. Fortunately, they’re not the only ones with big dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas are energy in its rawest form. They have the power to captivate us, inspire us, draw others to aid us, and make us do what we thought was impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every startup, political movement, book, and artistic expression started as a simple idea in someone’s head. Let’s face it, most ideas suck. Many that do work are iterated, subverted, and otherwise altered beyond recognition. However, without that spark of golden light, we’d never have the power to begin on our quest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ideas-allow-us-to-tell-great-stories&quot;&gt;Ideas allow us to tell great stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the founding fathers of the United States spoke of the idea of freedom (okay, they were really just fed up with taxes but bear with me), they were able to rally many of their fellow countrymen to take up arms and fight. Without the idea of freedom as a rallying cry, how many would have left the comfort of their homes to risk their lives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story they spun, with the British as evil tax-hungry (a burdensome two percent in 1775 New England) tea-sipping overlords, was so evocative that it changed the world forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is with startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you expect to inspire investors, co-founders, and customers to coalesce around your cause without an idea that gets them excited? Who are the bad guys you are fighting? How will you rally your troops? Are you, wielding your idea aloft like Excaliber, the hero?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-better-idea&quot;&gt;A better &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of pooh-poohing ideas, I say we embrace them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We acknowledge that they may need to change based upon customer feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We accept that for our idea to grow we must share it openly instead of keeping it to ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We understand that execution, persistance, and teamwork will bring us across the finishline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And then we finally give ideas the credit they are due.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We leverage them to build a team of fantastic professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We craft stories around them to engage with, learn from, and excite customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We let their vibrancy keep us warm when we feel overwhelmed or discouraged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we sit on their shoulders as they elevate us to new heights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 12:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>daleknauss.com/in-defense-of-ideas</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">daleknauss.com/in-defense-of-ideas</guid>
        
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
